<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<projects xmlns="http://www.savetheforest.com" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.savetheforest.com
                             projects.xsd">
    <project>
        <id>1</id>
        <title>Brazil, wildlife corridors</title>
        <description>The Atlantic Forest has been reduced to green fragments due to agricultural expansion. It used to be 6 times the size of the United Kingdom, 
            but it is now only a forest in name. Over the course of 20 years, it has lost over 80% of its original forest cover. No other large tropical forest has suffered this 
            much loss, which has affected the rich biodiversity in the area.</description>
        <image>project1.png</image>
        <goal>50000</goal>
        <raised>30000</raised>
    </project>
    <project>
        <id>1</id>
        <title>Madagascar Kalamboro</title>
        <description>Healthy mangroves were once widespread along the coast of Madagascar, capturing sediments that destroy coral reefs, sheltering highly diverse mollusc and 
            crustacean communities and providing resources for birds, sea turtles, manatees as well as the Malagasy people themselves. In the last decades, human activities in 
            the form of urban development, overfishing, rice farming, salt production and deforestation have caused the widespread destruction of this unique ecosystem. With its 
            rivers running ‘blood red’ staining the surrounding Indian Ocean from soil erosion brought about by deforestation, as early as 1983 astronauts remarked that is looked 
            as if Madagascar was bleeding to death. This metaphor highlights one of Madagascar's greatest environmental problems.</description>
        <image>project2.png</image>
        <goal>48624</goal>
        <raised>32481</raised>
    </project>
    <project>
        <id>2</id>
        <title>Philippines</title>
        <description>The aim of the restoration efforts was twofold, to plant trees in the Sarangani province and increase the health, education, income and overall well-being 
            of the local communities. The forest was restored using what is known as the framework species method, which involves planting a suite of native species to promote 
            more rapid natural succession. Through this, the proejcts aimed to restore the area's forest and biodiversity. Species were chosen to encourage the return of for 
            important indigeous species and provide important ecosystems services, like stabilising soils, maintaining the health of the water cycle and sequestering carbon from 
            the atmosphere. </description>
        <image>project3.png</image>
        <goal>68125</goal>
        <raised>65127</raised>
    </project>
    <project>
        <id>3</id>
        <title>Zambia Conservation</title>
        <description>Large swathes of forest are lost in Zambia annually, largely due to charcoal production and agriculture. Coupled with the high levels of poverty in the country, 
            this affords Zambia one of the highest rates of deforestation in the world. Deforestation and mono-cropping by farmers in the Luanshya district has resulted in a loss of 
            soil organic matter and threatens the future sustainability of local livelihoods.</description>
        <image>project4.png</image>
        <goal>50000</goal>
        <raised>30000</raised>
    </project>
    <project>
        <id>4</id>
        <title>Kenya Meru</title>
        <description>Kenya's forest once measured a mere 2% of the country's total land cover. Some of the most significant reserves of forest habitat reside in Mount Kenya national 
            park. Yet Mount Kenya is also facing severe deforestation rates, losing about 30% of its forest cover through illegal activities such as timber harvesting, shamba systems 
            (where agricultural crops are grown together with forest tree species) and charcoal burning. Such alarming rates threaten local wildlife and the liveilhoods of local 
            communities.</description>
        <image>project5.png</image>
        <goal>50000</goal>
        <raised>30000</raised>
    </project>
    <project>
        <id>5</id>
        <title>India Sirumalai</title>
        <description>The vegetation ranges from tropical thorn forest to mixed deciduous forest, dry evergreen forest, moist deciduous forest and semi-evergreen forest, all severely 
            degraded. The major causes of deforestation are expansion of farmland, charcoal and fuel wood production, utilization of wood for construction and grazing by cattle. Out of 
            all these, the major one is the population pressure, compelling farmers to encroach on the few remaining forested areas for farmland. As a result, land degradation, wild 
            life extinction, over-grazing and fodder shortage have occurred.</description>
        <image>project6.png</image>
        <goal>50000</goal>
        <raised>30000</raised>
    </project>
</projects>