<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<catalog xmlns="http://www.savetheforest.com"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.savetheforest.com
                             blog.xsd">
    <notice>
        <id>0</id>
        <date>2002-09-24</date>
        <title>Destruction of Primary Rainforests Increased by 12% from 2019 to 2020</title>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            The tropics lost 12.2 million acres of tree cover by 2020, according to University of Maryland data 
            released today. 
            <br>
            <br>  
            Of this total, 4.2 million hectares, an area the size of the Netherlands
            occurred in humid tropical primary forests, which are especially important for carbon storage and biodiversity. 
            Carbon emissions from this loss of primary forests (2.64 Gt CO2) are equivalent to annual emissions of 570 million 
            cars, more than double the number of vehicles circulating in the United States.
            <br>
            <br> 
            The loss of primary forests was 12% higher in 2020 compared to the previous year, and is the second consecutive year that the loss of primary forests worsened in the tropics.
            2020 should be a milestone in the fight against deforestation, a year in which many companies, countries and international organizations have pledged to reduce or stop forest loss altogether. 
            The continued losses of primary tropical forests make it clear that humanity has failed to achieve these goals.
            <br>
            <h3 class="mt-30 mb-30">The 10 countries where primary forests were most lost in 2020</h3>
            <ol class="ordered-list">
                <li><span>Brasil: 1.700.000</span></li>
                <li><span>RDC: 500.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Bolivia: 300.000</span>
                <li><span>Indonésia: 300.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Peru:198.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Colombia: 180.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Cameroon: 150.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Laos: 145.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Malasia: 144.000</span></li>
                <li><span>Mexico: 130.000</span></li>
            </ol>
            <br>
            As in previous years, deforestation for the opening of areas for commodity production was the main cause of loss of tree cover (in primary and secondary forests) in Latin America and Southeast Asia, 
            while rotational agriculture dominates in tropical Africa. In addition, fires and other climate-related impacts continued to be relevant in the tropics and other regions.
            ]]>
        </description>
        <image>news1.jpg</image>
        <publisher>Diogo Vaz</publisher>
        <category>Destruction of forests</category>
    </notice>
    <notice>
        <id>1</id>
        <date>2002-10-24</date>
        <title>Venezuelan People and Forests Suffer as Gold Mining Advances</title>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            Mining in the Amazon is a pervasive threat to the world’s largest rainforest and it’s on the rise. 
            Gold prices <strong>spiked</strong> last summer and have remained high. COVID-19-related stimulus packages supported 
            gold prices, and the economic threat posed by the pandemic turned investors towards the seemingly stable 
            investment in gold. Demand for the metal has accelerated. And where demand has grown, deforestation and 
            human rights abuses have followed. 
            <br>
            <br>
            Venezuela’s rainforests and people have been hit particularly 
            hard by gold mining, where estimates indicate that between <strong>80% and 90%</strong> is mined illegally.
            <br>
            <br>
            <h2>Gold mining replaces oil industry, with the potential to be just as destructive</h2>
            <br>
            Venezuela has been historically dependent on extractive industries; until recently, the country’s economy was built on government-controlled petroleum extraction. After the oil industry collapsed due 
            to crumbling infrastructure, the government was looking for a way to bolster <strong>the economy and gold</strong> offered a potential salve. 
            <br>
            <br>
            In 2016, the President of Venezuela, Nicolás Maduro, announced plans for the
            Arco Minero, which designates 112,000 square kilometers of rainforest south of the Orinoco River for mining gold and coltan (a mineral used in many electronics). 
            <br>
            <br>            
            The plan for the Arco Minero <strong> explicitly contradicts </strong> environmental standards laid out in the country’s constitution. Many of the mines are run by Venezuelan gangs or guerilla groups from Colombia under protection from the Venezuelan military,
            creating a <strong>landscape of lawlessness</strong>.
            <br>
            <br>
            Illegal goldmining had been occurring south of the Orinoco since before the Arco Minero, but never on such a massive scale. Cesar Romero, a metallurgical engineer, director of Fundacion Cerlas and 
            co-founder of “Plataforma contra el Arco Minero”— an activist organization that opposes the mining— recalls his shock at just how much territory had been approved for <strong>mining</strong>.
            <br>
            <br>
            <blockquote class="generic-blockquote"> “When I read the decree, 
                I couldn’t believe the dimension. The activity was bad before, but the Arco Minero made it huge,” said Romero. “The area established by the decree is more than 12% of the national territory, bigger 
                than Cuba and some European countries.”</blockquote>
            <h2>An arc of destruction eating into the rainforest</h2>
            <br>
            Since the declaration in 2016, mining has proliferated, transforming Bolivar and Amazonas state where most of the activity is concentrated. 
            <br>
            <br>
            Vilisa Morón-Zambrano, President of the Sociedad Venezolana 
            de Ecologica (SVE) which has been investigating the ecological impacts of the Arco Minero since 2016, has traveled to the region several times and remarked how quickly things have changed.
            <br>
            <br>
            <blockquote class="generic-blockquote"> “In 2014 I was there for tourism, and the mining was not evident. But last February, once you pass some of the main towns and find the road to Brazil, it’s shocking, it’s all over,”</blockquote>
            Morón-Zambrano said.
            <br>
            <blockquote class="generic-blockquote"> “You’d see people with craft equipment for mining walking around, and you could also see extraction plant sites in plain sight.”</blockquote>
            ]]>
        </description>
        <image>news2.jpg</image>
        <publisher>David Ferreira</publisher>
        <category>Destruction of forests</category>
    </notice>
    <notice>
        <id>2</id>
        <date>2002-12-12</date>
        <title>Supplied with Tech, Indigenous Forest Monitors Curb Deforestation</title>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            Loreto, Peru — A forest monitor from the Indigenous community of Vista Hermosa checks her smartphone. 
            A satellite map showing the forest around her pops up. Her community’s territory is outlined and 
            pink pixels—deforestation alerts—are visible within the boundaries. She and her fellow forest monitors 
            react quickly, patrolling to the alert to confirm the deforestation. Finding the stumps and area cleared, 
            they snap some photos and record their observations, and return to their community to relay the information 
            and decide what to do next.
            <br>
            <br>
            Vista Hermosa, along with 75 other communities in the Northeastern region of Peru are participants in a two-year randomized control trial, conducted by researchers at New from Johns Hopkins University 
            and New York University, in partnership with the <strong> Rainforest Foundation US (RFUS), ORPIO </strong> to determine whether equipping Indigenous communities with satellite data could help bring
            deforestation rates down.
            <br>
            <br>
            The results, released today in the <strong> Proceedings of the National Academies of Sciences </strong>, found that communities that implemented technology-based forest monitoring saw a 
            reduction of 52% in the first year and 21% in the second year, compared to similar territories that did not change their monitoring practices. The most significant reductions were in communities 
            facing the most immediate threats to their forests. These findings have implications for deforestation prevention strategies across the Amazon as a low-cost, <strong> high-return strategy </strong> to combat climate change.
            <br>
            <br>
            <h2>You Can’t Prevent Deforestation If You Can’t See It</h2>
            <br>
            The premise of the study was simple — in order to effectively act against deforestation within their territories, Indigenous communities first must be able to quickly detect it. Satellites offered a 
            solution. Orbiting and imaging the Earth constantly, they can show changes in forest cover between images on tiny scales. These images are used to build GLAD alerts, updated weekly on the GFW platform 
            to show likely instances of deforestation, as well as the weekly alerts produced by Peru’s Ministry of the Environment. 
            <br>
            <br>
            But these systems rely on technology access to use. Often the places where the use 
            of alerts could have the biggest impact are deep in the rainforest, with no access to the internet or cell service.
            <br>
            <br>
            <blockquote class="generic-blockquote">“What good does the information do if it’s only seen by a bunch of academics and people in glass buildings?” said Tom Bewick, Peru Country Director for the Rainforest Foundation US, who was a principal 
            architect of the study’s monitoring program. “The whole point is putting it into action.”</blockquote> 
                
            So, in order to put the data into action, RFUS provided each participating community with smartphones and 
            training on the use of the phones, alerts and drones. Then, once per month, a courier would hand deliver the latest alert data along with maps and GPS coordinates to each community on a thumb drive. 
            Community monitors could then transfer the data to their phones and access it offline to conduct patrols. The hope was that timely follow-up on the alerts would allow communities to stop deforestation 
            in its tracks.
            <br>
            <br>
            <h2>Elected Monitors Represent Their Communities</h2>
            <br>
            ORPIO and the researchers identified 76 communities to participate in the study. Through a randomized lottery, 39 communities were selected to participate in the active monitoring program and 37 
            communities were designated to serve as controls. Later, three of the 39 selected communities decided not to participate. 
            
            <br>
            <br>
            Communities participating in the study selected three members to serve as forest 
            monitors, who would take responsibility for investigating deforestation alerts in their territories. Forest monitors received a daily stipend of $8 (USD) while out on patrols.
            <br>
            <br>
            When an alert was verified 
            to be unauthorized clearing, monitors documented and brought their evidence back to the community to make collective decisions about how to follow up. Often, trees are cut by outsiders, either to 
            illegally harvest logs, clear for agriculture, or cultivate coca for cocaine production. 
            <br>
            <br>
            Sometimes communities decide to confront the encroachers themselves. This was the case in Vista Hermosa, 
            where, when shown the satellite images of their clandestine operations, the culprits decided to abandon the clearing. In other cases, communities have compiled reports to provide to the environmental 
            authorities in Peru, who have then taken actions against the perpetrators. 
            <br>
            <br>
            Regardless of what a community decided to do with the information, having designated monitors reduced decision-making delays 
            that could otherwise stall the response to encroachment. A comparison of the 36 participating communities to 37 control groups that maintained their typical monitoring practices found that monitoring 
            activity intensified in communities where authority was invested in monitors. The average rate of territorial patrols and corresponding deforestation reports doubled in the first year. 
            <br>
            <br>
            <h2>Community Monitoring Methods Can be Replicated Elsewhere</h2>
            <br>
            What the results of this study show is that investing in forest communities improves their capacity to protect their own territories, and this results in averted deforestation. 
            <br>
            <br>
            Bewick says that the model demonstrated by the project in Loreto could be adapted and expanded across the Amazon. According to the study, adopting similar local governance 
            strategies in Peru could save 134,000 of 500,000 hectares of forests likely to be lost over the next decade. In Brazil, 300,000 of 2.2 million hectares of deforestation could be 
            averted in the same time scale. 
            <br>
            <br>
                <blockquote class="generic-blockquote">“There’s a solution here, it’s cost effective, and it works. This would be a good investment for the future, not only for Peru but for our planet.”</blockquote>
                Bewick said.
                <br>
                <br>
            ]]>
        </description>
        <image>news3.jpg</image>
        <publisher>Diogo Vaz</publisher>
        <category>Technologies for saving forests</category>
    </notice>
    <notice>
        <id>3</id>
        <date>2021-05-24</date>
        <title>2021 Must Be a Turning Point for Forests. 2020 Data Shows Us Why</title>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            More than 12 million hectares of tree cover in the tropics was lost in 2020 alone, according to analysis 
            of University of Maryland data by WRI. Most alarmingly, that included 4.2 million hectares of previously 
            undisturbed primary tropical forests.This loss represents a crisis for climate stability and biodiversity 
            conservation, as well as a humanitarian disaster and lost economic opportunity. This analysis now covering 
            20 years of data shows all that’s been lost — as well as the interventions that work.
            <br>
            In a year when everything else slowed down, forest loss sped up.
            <br>
            The COVID-19 pandemic disrupted lives and livelihoods around the world, and the global economy contracted by around 3.5% in 2020. Yet despite the economic downturn, the loss of primary tropical forests 
            ticked up by 12% compared to 2019, continuing an upward trend. Pandemic-related lockdowns probably contributed to short-term increases in forest loss in some cases by limiting the mobility of law 
            enforcement officials and forcing urban-rural migration, but the more significant impacts of the pandemic on forests are likely yet to come.
            <br>
            Unless they see alternatives, governments grappling with constrained fiscal resources and high levels of debt will be tempted to cut the budgets of environmental agencies and license new investment 
            projects that could show up in forest loss data in future years. And yet new studies (here and here) are finding that investments in conserving and restoring nature actually provide more effective 
            stimulus than traditional measures.
            <br>
            Forests are increasingly falling victim to climate change.
            <br>
            The most ominous signal from the 2020 data is the number and variety of instances in which forests themselves suffered in extreme weather events. In the Amazon, burning now occurs inside the rainforest, 
            rather than just along the recently felled edges. Even wetlands are burning! Global warming and forest loss conspire to create warmer, drier conditions, which in turn render forests more vulnerable to 
            fire and pest infestation. Subsequent burning and decay release more carbon emissions, feeding a vicious cycle.
            <br>
            Nature has been whispering to us about these risks for a long time, but now she is shouting. The longer we wait to both stop deforestation and shift to net-zero emissions trajectories in other sectors, 
            the more likely it is that our natural carbon sinks will go up in smoke.
            <br>
            20 years of data demonstrate what works.
            <br>
            Although the overall trends are distressing, what’s happened in a few individual countries inspires confidence that the drivers of deforestation can be defeated.
            <br>
            Indonesia has now reduced deforestation for four years in a row. Favorable weather, low commodity prices and implementation of corporate commitments to get deforestation out of commodity supply chains 
            have undoubtedly contributed to that trend. But the Indonesian government’s effort also deserves credit. In the aftermath of devastating fires in 2015, the government beefed up fire prevention and 
            monitoring, and expanded moratoria on conversion of primary forests and peatlands.
            <br>
            What’s significant about the Indonesia story is that it’s been driven by a combination of domestic self-interest — avoiding the severe public health and other costs of fires — and international market 
            and financial incentives. Perhaps it’s not a coincidence that one of the provinces that experienced a steep drop in tree cover loss in 2020 was East Kalimantan, which just concluded an agreement with 
            the World Bank for up to $110 million in REDD+ finance if the province is successful in bringing down forest-based emissions. The province is also host to one of most mature multisector, multistakeholder 
            initiatives in the country seeking to transition to more sustainable land use. Under a Green Growth Compact launched in 2016, government agencies, NGOs and the private sector have been coordinating 
            <br>
            What should be done to save forests now?
            <br>
            These are fragile gains. We’ve seen this movie before. Brazil achieved a huge reduction in deforestation in the Amazon by deploying a suite of proven policy and market interventions, but now we’re 
            witnessing a heartbreaking unraveling of that success: The Brazilian Amazon experienced a 15% increase in primary forest loss in 2020 compared to 2019. The policies and rhetoric of the Bolsonaro 
            administration have crippled environmental agencies and law enforcement, encouraged land-grabbing, and put indigenous territories at risk. In the coming months, Indonesia will face rising 
            palm oil prices and pressure to approve forest-risk investments under a recent job creation law, even as a three-year moratorium on licensing of new oil palm plantations is set to expire this year. 
            For Indonesia to maintain its success and other countries to follow its lead, the voices of domestic constituencies for forest protection need to be amplified. Space must be maintained for independent 
            monitoring and advocacy by civil society. The international community needs to ramp up incentives for those governments undertaking serious efforts to address deforestation to create a value proposition 
            for staying the course. Such incentives should include preferential market access for forest-risk commodities that are produced legally and sustainably. Governments should be able to count on financial 
            reward and diplomatic recognition for success in bringing down forest-based emissions. They should also have access to the investment funds, debt relief, and technical support they need to embark on 
            genuinely green post-pandemic recovery efforts.
            <br>
            Forest guardians matter
            <br>
            It’s also important to remember that the forest loss that is visible from satellites has profound impacts on the people and communities on the ground who depend on forests for their health, safety and 
            livelihoods. Their lives matter. What we can see from satellites is that when indigenous peoples are present in forests and their rights are strengthened, forest cover is maintained. Yet the number of 
            forest defenders being murdered is rising along with the rate of forest loss.
            <br>
            With global climate summits on climate change and biodiversity on the calendar, 2021 is a year for solidarity among governments committed to averting the worst impacts of forest loss. It’s also time 
            for solidarity with the communities risking their lives to save the world’s remaining forests. Let’s make 2021 the year that we finally muster the political will and financial resources to ensure that 
            their efforts are successful.
            ]]>
        </description>
        <image>news4.jpg</image>
        <publisher>Diogo Vaz</publisher>
        <category>Destruction of forests</category>
    </notice>
    <notice>
        <id>4</id>
        <date>2021-05-24</date>
        <title>THE FORESTS ARE BURNING IN THE AMAZON AGAIN...</title>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            It’s the dry season in Brazil, and forest fires are spreading again. Though some can be caused 
            naturally by factors such as lightning strikes, most are actually started by farmers and loggers 
            clearing land for crops or grazing.
            <br>
            Now, with blazes already at a 13-year high as early as June, this year's fires could equal or even surpass the devastating fires of August 2019, when parts of the Amazon burned at a rate not seen 
            in years. Ecologists argued that the damage was a direct consequence of the government’s environmental negligence. Brazil’s present  government wants to open the rainforest for business, despite the 
            country previously showing a willingness to protect the Amazon as a key part of its environmental policy. An Amazon Fund was created in 2008, and deforestation slowed from 2004 to 2012 and again between 
            2016 and 2017. In 2019, deforestation of the region spiked again as previous governments’ efforts to fight the illegal clearance of trees were pulled back. Last summer alone, more forest had been cleared 
            than in the last three years. It was only when Bolsonaro bowed to pressure to enforce a 60-day ban on setting fires to clear land in the Amazon that the fires slowed down. Their number dropped by a third 
            between August and September 2019. Last year, with our partner IDESAM, we supported crucial firefighting activities in Apuí, the municipality with the highest rate of fire outbreaks in the Amazon. 
            With our support, the Prevfogo de Apuí fire brigade was able to increase its firefighting efforts and prevent new outbreaks with a new water pump, hoses and a truck. Local schools had fire awareness 
            sessions, and training was held for brigade volunteers. In the long term SaveTheForest and its local partner plan to cultivate new forest-friendly incomes for the farmers, meaning that communities don’t 
            have to resort to logging or using the forests for food for their animals. This year we need to support the firefighting again, especially as the COVID-19 crisis is hitting Brazil more than any other 
            country in the world, making every challenge bigger. By July this year, 828 fire outbreaks had been registered, the highest rate since 2010. In PA Rio Juma, the settlement with the most outbreaks, 
            we’ll be supporting the brigade and offering training once again, as well as ensuring that the coffee plantation where we plan to integrate agroforestry actions next year is well protected by firebreaks.
            ]]>
        </description>
        <image>news5.jpg</image>
        <publisher>David Ferreira</publisher>
        <category>Amazon</category>
    </notice>
    <notice>
        <id>5</id>
        <date>2021-05-24</date>
        <title>Just 7 Commodities Replaced an Area of Forest Twice the Size of Germany from 2001-2015</title>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            New analysis shows that just seven agricultural commodities — cattle, oil palm, soy, cocoa, rubber, coffee and plantation wood fiber — accounted for
            26% of global tree cover loss from 2001 to 2015. These agricultural commodities replaced 71.9 million hectares of forest during that period, an area of land more 
            than twice the size of Germany.

            <h3 class="mt-30 mb-30">Total forest replacement by analyzed commodities (2001-15)</h3>

            <div class="mb-30">
                <table class="progress-table">
                    <thead>
                        <tr class="table-head">
                            <th class="serial">#</th>
                            <th class="country">Desforestation</th>
                            <th class="visit">Million hectares</th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/cattle.png" alt="flag">Cattle</th>
                            <th class="visit">45.1</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/oil_palm.png" alt="flag">Oil Palm</th>
                            <th class="visit">10.5</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/soy.png" alt="flag">Soy</th>
                            <th class="visit">8.2</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/cocoa.png" alt="flag">Cocoa</th>
                            <th class="visit">2.3</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/plantation_rubber.png" alt="flag">Plantation Rubber</th>
                            <th class="visit">2.1</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/coffee.png" alt="flag">Coffee</th>
                            <th class="visit">1.9</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr class="table-row">
                            <th class="serial">01</th>
                            <th class="country"> <img src="xml/blog/images/news6/plantation_wood_fiber.png" alt="flag">Plantation wood fiber</th>
                            <th class="visit">1.8</th>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </div>
            
            What is Agriculture’s Role in Deforestation?
            As demand for food and other resources continues to grow, forests are often cleared to make way for new fields and plantations. Scientists estimate that over a 
            quarter of tropical forests and just under half of temperate forests have been converted to production in human history.
            Today, the majority of tree cover loss associated with the expansion of farms and plantations happens in the tropics, a troubling trend considering the vast 
            carbon stocks and biodiversity held in rainforests. While we have a general understanding of where agribusiness has replaced forests, until now the world lacked 
            information about the impact of specific products. Our analysis compares the current extent of seven commodities with annual tree cover loss data from 2001 to 2015 to 
            map where each commodity replaced forests over that time span.
            <br>
            Cattle Ranching Replaced More Forests than Any Other Commodity
            Of the seven agricultural commodities, cattle pasture replaced the most forest by far — 45.1 million hectares, or an area of land the size of Sweden. Cattle are responsible for 16% of total tree 
            cover loss. Oil palm is a distant second, replacing 10.5 million hectares from 2001 to 2015, while soy accounted for 7.9 million hectares. Cocoa, plantation rubber, plantation wood fiber and 
            coffee each replaced around 2 million hectares of forest from 2001 to 2015, though the analyses for rubber and wood fiber cover only a subset of countries because of data availability. Oil palm replaced 
            forests mostly in Indonesia and Malaysia, while soy replaced forests mainly in South American countries like Brazil and Argentina. The conversion of forests to cattle pasture was more widely distributed 
            across the globe, but hotspots exist in South and Central America. Cocoa, rubber, wood fiber and coffee played a big role in replacing forests in some countries, despite their smaller global impacts. 
            In Ghana, for example, conversion of forests to cocoa represents a third of the country’s total tree cover loss. The seven commodities analyzed represent 57% of agriculture-related tree cover loss from 
            2001-2015.]]>
        </description>
        <image>news6.jpg</image>
        <publisher>Diogo Vaz</publisher>
        <category>Deforestation</category>
    </notice>
</catalog>
